<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Academic on Clinical Research Facility - Cork || Statistics and Data Analysis Unit</title>
    <link>/tags/academic/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Academic on Clinical Research Facility - Cork || Statistics and Data Analysis Unit</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Aug 2018 12:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/academic/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Science @ UCC</title>
      <link>/post/openscienceucc/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Aug 2018 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/openscienceucc/</guid>
      <description>The goal of Open Science @ UCC, a 3 day workshop running from October 31 to November 2 (2018) at University College Cork, is to motivate and train 30 open science champions, who will work to support open science in their local research environments.
The event will be a mixture of lectures, tutorials, and participant-driven un-conferencing. There will also be plenty of time for small-group discussion and other socializing. Participants will thus leave the workshop as skilled, confident advocates for open science, connected to a network of other open science experts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dealing with negative trial results</title>
      <link>/post/negative_results/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jul 2018 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/negative_results/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to the world of clinical trials. You&amp;rsquo;ve got a great idea that has real potential to improve health. But I have some bad news for you. Are you ready?
Your intervention won&amp;rsquo;t work. I’m sorry. It won’t. Not even a little.
&amp;ldquo;But hold on a minute,&amp;rdquo; you say. &amp;ldquo;I haven’t even run the trial yet. How can you possibly know it won’t work?&amp;rdquo; Experience my friend – and as any experienced trialist can tell you, the intervention never works.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HRB CRFC Open Science Challenge Week 3</title>
      <link>/post/2018-05-09-ocs-wk3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 May 2018 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018-05-09-ocs-wk3/</guid>
      <description>Thanks again to everyone who came to Week 2 of the Open Science Challenge. If you haven’t made it yet, no worries, you are welcome to join us any time (but if you want me to stop emailing you, let me know).
Our next meeting will be Friday, May 18 at 2-3 pm in WGB room 4.05, where we will have a visit from Vicky Hellon from F1000 to talk about HRB Open Research.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HRB CRFC Open Science Challenge - Week 2</title>
      <link>/post/2018-04-23-osc-wk2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Apr 2018 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018-04-23-osc-wk2/</guid>
      <description>Thank you to everyone who came to our first session of the HRB Open Science Challenge. If you weren’t able to make it, no problem – we’ll catch you at the next session on May 4th, in room 4.05 of the Western Gateway Building (10:30 to 11:30), when we’ll be discussing what makes a good research question. Please give some thought to that before we meet, as well as what data you might/will use for your project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HRB CRFC Open Science Challenge</title>
      <link>/post/2018-04-06-osc-wk1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Apr 2018 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018-04-06-osc-wk1/</guid>
      <description>I’m a big fan of open science, and regularly argue for its importance. Strangely, however, I’ve never actually used many of the available open science tools. It&amp;rsquo;s just too damn easy to keep going with the status quo. That stops today!
Starting on Friday, April 20, Brendan and I will be hosting the HRB CRFC Open Science challenge. The challenge will be open until the end of the year, during which we will meet 2 or 3 times per month to develop an open science research project.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>