<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Clinical Research Facility - Cork || Statistics and Data Analysis Unit</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Clinical Research Facility - Cork || Statistics and Data Analysis Unit</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 May 2018 12:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>HRB CRFC Open Science Challenge - Week 3</title>
      <link>/post/2018-05-09-osc-wk3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 May 2018 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018-05-09-osc-wk3/</guid>
      <description>Thanks again to everyone who came to Week 2 of the Open Science Challenge. If you haven’t made it yet, no worries, you are welcome to join us any time (but if you want me to stop emailing you, let me know).
Our next meeting will be Friday, May 18 at 2-3 pm in WGB room 4.05, where we will have a visit from Vicky Hellon from F1000 to talk about HRB Open Research.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HRB CRFC Open Science Challenge - Week 2</title>
      <link>/post/2018-04-23-osc-wk2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Apr 2018 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018-04-23-osc-wk2/</guid>
      <description>Thank you to everyone who came to our first session of the HRB Open Science Challenge. If you weren’t able to make it, no problem – we’ll catch you at the next session on May 4th, in room 4.05 of the Western Gateway Building (10:30 to 11:30), when we’ll be discussing what makes a good research question. Please give some thought to that before we meet, as well as what data you might/will use for your project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HRB CRFC Open Science Challenge</title>
      <link>/post/2018-04-06-osc-wk1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Apr 2018 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018-04-06-osc-wk1/</guid>
      <description>I’m a big fan of open science, and regularly argue for its importance. Strangely, however, I’ve never actually used many of the available open science tools. It&amp;rsquo;s just too damn easy to keep going with the status quo. That stops today!
Starting on Friday, April 20, Brendan and I will be hosting the HRB CRFC Open Science challenge. The challenge will be open until the end of the year, during which we will meet 2 or 3 times per month to develop an open science research project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Magical clusters</title>
      <link>/post/cluster/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/cluster/</guid>
      <description>I was greeted today with the news that there are 5, not 2, types of diabetes. This is earth-shattering if you are a diabetologist or diabetes researcher. However, I soon as I saw the term “data-driven clustering” I knew I could probably relax.
For the uninitiated, data-driven clustering techniques can seem magical. The basic premise is that you take a sample, measure lots of things about them, and then feed all those data into an algorithm that will divide your sample into mutually exclusive groups.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/post/2018-05-09-osc-wk3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018-05-09-osc-wk3/</guid>
      <description>code{white-space: pre;}pre:not([class]) {background-color: white;}if (window.hljs) {hljs.configure({languages: []});hljs.initHighlightingOnLoad();if (document.readyState &amp;&amp; document.readyState === &#34;complete&#34;) {window.setTimeout(function() { hljs.initHighlighting(); }, 0);}}h1 {font-size: 34px;}h1.title {font-size: 38px;}h2 {font-size: 30px;}h3 {font-size: 24px;}h4 {font-size: 18px;}h5 {font-size: 16px;}h6 {font-size: 12px;}.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>