<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Clinical Research Facility - Cork || Statistics and Data Analysis Unit</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Clinical Research Facility - Cork || Statistics and Data Analysis Unit</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Nov 2018 12:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Trial Methods Week 1 - Reading Notes (Draft 1.0)</title>
      <link>/post/trial_methods_wk_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Nov 2018 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/trial_methods_wk_1/</guid>
      <description>Week 1 - Introduction The goals of week 1 are to:
 Welcome everyone and introduce the module Explain the role of the statistician and their role on the trial team Motivate an interest in proper clinical trial design and analysis Introduce the most fundamental aspects of trial design, and justify the importance of control and randomization.  Welcome I want to welcome you all to this module on Clinical Trial Design and Analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1-day R workshop for experienced users - Oct 30, 2018</title>
      <link>/post/rworkshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Oct 2018 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/rworkshop/</guid>
      <description>Overview: R is a programming language and free software environment for statistical computing and graphics. User instruction in R is often limited to course specific content, that focuses primarily on statistical operations through the base R package. R functionality extends far beyond this and across research fields. When combined with the RStudio GUI, R can be utilised as a powerful tool that encompasses data cleaning, exploration, visualisation and documentation operations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Science @ University College Cork (Oct 31 to Nov 2)</title>
      <link>/post/openscienceucc/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Aug 2018 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/openscienceucc/</guid>
      <description>Open Science @ UCC is a 3 day workshop running from October 31 to November 2 (2018) at University College Cork.
Open science practices help make research accessible, transparent, and replicable. Research funders (including H2020, SFI and HRB) are recognising the long term benefits to open science and new grant calls increasingly reflect this. The challenge for researchers is to become aware of the available options, and explore ways in which they can apply these techniques to their day-to-day research workflows.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dealing with negative trial results</title>
      <link>/post/negative_results/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jul 2018 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/negative_results/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to the world of clinical trials. You&amp;rsquo;ve got a great idea that has real potential to improve health. But I have some bad news for you. Are you ready?
Your intervention won&amp;rsquo;t work. I’m sorry. It won’t. Not even a little.
&amp;ldquo;But hold on a minute,&amp;rdquo; you say. &amp;ldquo;I haven’t even run the trial yet. How can you possibly know it won’t work?&amp;rdquo; Experience my friend – and as any experienced trialist can tell you, the intervention never works.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HRB CRFC Open Science Challenge Week 3</title>
      <link>/post/2018-05-09-ocs-wk3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 May 2018 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018-05-09-ocs-wk3/</guid>
      <description>Thanks again to everyone who came to Week 2 of the Open Science Challenge. If you haven’t made it yet, no worries, you are welcome to join us any time (but if you want me to stop emailing you, let me know).
Our next meeting will be Friday, May 18 at 2-3 pm in WGB room 4.05, where we will have a visit from Vicky Hellon from F1000 to talk about HRB Open Research.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HRB CRFC Open Science Challenge - Week 2</title>
      <link>/post/2018-04-23-osc-wk2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Apr 2018 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018-04-23-osc-wk2/</guid>
      <description>Thank you to everyone who came to our first session of the HRB Open Science Challenge. If you weren’t able to make it, no problem – we’ll catch you at the next session on May 4th, in room 4.05 of the Western Gateway Building (10:30 to 11:30), when we’ll be discussing what makes a good research question. Please give some thought to that before we meet, as well as what data you might/will use for your project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HRB CRFC Open Science Challenge</title>
      <link>/post/2018-04-06-osc-wk1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Apr 2018 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018-04-06-osc-wk1/</guid>
      <description>I’m a big fan of open science, and regularly argue for its importance. Strangely, however, I’ve never actually used many of the available open science tools. It&amp;rsquo;s just too damn easy to keep going with the status quo. That stops today!
Starting on Friday, April 20, Brendan and I will be hosting the HRB CRFC Open Science challenge. The challenge will be open until the end of the year, during which we will meet 2 or 3 times per month to develop an open science research project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Magical clusters</title>
      <link>/post/cluster/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/cluster/</guid>
      <description>I was greeted today with the news that there are 5, not 2, types of diabetes. This is earth-shattering if you are a diabetologist or diabetes researcher. However, I soon as I saw the term “data-driven clustering” I knew I could probably relax.
For the uninitiated, data-driven clustering techniques can seem magical. The basic premise is that you take a sample, measure lots of things about them, and then feed all those data into an algorithm that will divide your sample into mutually exclusive groups.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code of Conduct for Open Science @ UCC (2018)</title>
      <link>/post/codeofconduct/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2017 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/codeofconduct/</guid>
      <description>Summary The Organizers of Open Science @ UCC are dedicated to providing a harassment-free experience for everyone, regardless of gender, gender identity and expression, sexual orientation, disability, physical appearance, body size, race, age or religion (or lack thereof). We will not tolerate harassment of participants in any form. Sexual language and imagery is not appropriate for any aspect of the workshop. Participants violating these rules may be sanctioned or expelled from the workshop, without a refund, at the discretion of the organizers.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>